<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>User on Product Debut</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/user/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User on Product Debut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 09:20:15 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/user/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Products: The Role of Strategic Thinking in Growth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 09:20:15 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/scaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a product grows, scaling becomes one of the most challenging yet rewarding aspects of product management. A strong product strategy can guide this process. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I approach scaling products in the Fintech space:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-for-scalability-from-day-one&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building for Scalability from Day One&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When launching a product, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to focus on immediate user needs, but I always keep scalability in mind. By working closely with engineers, I ensure that the product architecture can handle increasing user demand without compromising performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Empathy is My Best Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 09:20:15 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/empathy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a product manager in the Fintech space, &lt;strong&gt;empathy&lt;/strong&gt; is one of the most powerful tools I’ve relied on to develop products that truly serve users. A product that isn’t designed with empathy for the user’s experience will fall short, regardless of its however many technical features. Here’s how I put empathy into practice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-research-the-foundation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Research: The Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before diving into the development of a product, I always ensure that we have a deep understanding of the &lt;strong&gt;user’s pain points&lt;/strong&gt;. This involves conducting user interviews, surveys, and gathering feedback from various touchpoints. By immersing myself in the &lt;strong&gt;user’s world&lt;/strong&gt;, I can identify what problems they are trying to solve and how to create a solution that fits seamlessly into their lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Balancing UX and Business Acumen in Product Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/third/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 14:28:15 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/third/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is more of a note than an article, a culmination of what I am learning by scouring the internet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a product manager, one of the most critical skills I&amp;rsquo;ve developed over the last year is the ability to balance &lt;strong&gt;user experience (UX)&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;business acumen&lt;/strong&gt;. Both elements are crucial for building products that not only meet user needs but also drive business growth. Here’s how I approach this balance:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
